

EXPERIENCE

Senior Product Designer

OfficeSpace Software Nov 2021 – Present

- •Lead design and implementation of new design system that triples dev velocity, reduces accessibility issues by 70%, and unlocks thousands in new ARR
- Work across multiple teams to ship new product features and enhancements, including a suite of business intelligence dashboards that has directly increased NRR and revolutionized data workflows for WEX teams
- Deliver at every step of the product development lifecycle, including running UX research, leading design workshops, and providing high fidelity design mockups

Senior UI/UX Designer

Simple Focus Oct 2015 – Oct 2021

- Oversaw design and dev teams in the production of websites, apps, and real-world experiences, including the implementation of creative growth programs
- Designed and built responsive, performant websites and apps on a variety of platforms using React/JS, HTML/CSS, and PHP
- Developed additional skills in motion graphics, 3D, and projection mapping to create rich interactive experiences that earned 2 Gold and 4 Silver Addy's
- · Worked directly with clients ranging from local non-profits to Fortune-500s

Product Designer

HelloHome (Freelance) June 2017 – July 2018

- Worked directly with startup founder and CTO to bring their vision of an end-to-end real estate sales platform to life from scratch
- Created a design system, dozens of user flows, and innovative user interface concepts for initial product launch

Web Designer

Red Alloy Creative Dec 2013 – Oct 2015

- Led discovery, design, and development of web and interactive projects
- Expanded service offerings by providing site architecture, content strategy, and brand voice guidelines that enriched the client experience
- Helped grow the business from a solo founder to a 3-person team that was later acquired

EDUCATION

Rhodes College

Memphis, Tenn. English & Creative Writing (Cum Laude) Sigma Tau Delta May 2012

ABOUT ME

A design leader with 10 years of expertise in UI/UX and design systems. I consistently deliver business value through the practice of user-centered design, and strengthen teams through peer mentorship and deep collaboration with front-end developers.

CERTIFICATIONS

Product Psychology Mastery Growth.Design July 2021

PUBLICATIONS

Smashing Magazine Better Search UX Through Microcopy – 2019

COMMUNITY

AIGA Memphis Executive Board Member, Director of Communications 2017-2018

Designation Design Mentor 2016-2017

LINKS

andrewmillen.com linkedin.com/in/andrew-millen/ codepen.com/andrewmillen github.com/andrewmillen

CONTACT

andrewmillen1@gmail.com 901-491-5586